KIPRONO COLLINS KIRUI FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

P.O. BOX 357-20106

+254 700 362 626

collinskirui23@gmail.com

www.kipronocollins.com

Profile

Front-End Web Developer with experience in Design and Code, all thanks to Adobe XD for the designing process and HTML5, Css3 & JavaScript to transform the design to code and publishing. Also use Visual Studio Code as my main text editor.

Skills

- HTML5 Scripting
- Css3 Styling
- JavaScript Programming Language
- Adobe XD Designing Software
- Figma Designing Software
- Visual Studio Code Text Editor
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook & Publisher)

Work Experience

Freelance Website Design & Coding for A School Kipsonoi Secondary School

July 2022 - Present

www.kipsonoisec.com

- Website Design with Adobe XD
- Scripted with HTML5
- Styled with Css3
- Made the Website dynamic with JavaScript
- Published it to the web and hosted via Netlify.com

County Government of Nakuru

September 2021 -December 2021

Human Resource, Nakuru Main Office

ICT Department, Attachment

- Debugging HTML Code
- Adding HTML Elements to the existing County Website (anchor tags & optimizing images)
- Troubleshooting Computers
- Troubleshooting Networks
- Creating Slides in PowerPoint
- Typing documents in Microsoft Word

County Government of Nakuru

Njoro Sub - County Office

- Processing trade licenses from the County Government portal
- Registering traders to the County Government portal
- Maintaining printers
- Typing documents in Microsoft Word

Apollo Agriculture

January 2018 – April 2018

Field Agent, Elburgon Ward

- Capturing farmer's details on the company's app and uploading to the company's servers for loan review
- Using the company's app to measure the size of land the farmer owns to determine the amount of loan they qualify for
- Taking pictures of the farmer's information and making sure they are submitted to the servers using the app
- Editing farmer's details on the company's app
- Making follow-ups on the progress of the farmer's loan application

Education

Diploma in Information Communication Technology 2021 – 2022 The Eldoret National Polytechnic

Craft Certificate in Information Communication Technology 2018 -2019

The Eldoret National Polytechnic

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education 2013 – 2017

Kabartegan High School

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education 2004 – 2012

Keringet Boarding Primary School

Referees

Mr. Gregory Rotich Principal, Kipsonoi Secondary School +254 723 380 687 grotich2@gmail.com

Mr. Caleb Jumbe Lecturer, The Eldoret National Polytechnic +254 710 869 845 dv.caleb@gmail.com